And I'll call the order of the regular meeting of the Madam City Council for Monday, June 28th.
Public input or on schedule personal appearances.
I don't think we have any to do.
I'm three consent agenda staff recommends we approve items 4, 3, 12.
I have to point out that I've been advised that we need to remove, remove,
or let them be.
And that's the role as I'm going to initiate the meeting.
Okay.
So do we need to pull 11 out and move on?
The separate layer just pull B out of it.
We can just, when the motion is made to approve everything on the consent agenda,
except for 11 B.
Okay.
I'll make a motion we approve the consent agenda.
All but 11 B.
Second.
Parker.
Why?
He's dead.
Davis.
Uncle.
Hi.
I'm 13 update on the new peats that can be in the store on Main Street.
Mr. Rusty Newman.
She's new.
So our next meeting is.
Since then, 74.
And as a 515.
I set my fund up for 49 support.
That's not change.
Adam, we take the go home.
I appreciate Kevin Cole's here.
He does a lot of our real estate and development on it.
And really helps out by on that.
My position.
Project major.
I usually come in.
We'll get.
Give it to the city.
Give it to council.
Get all this stuff together.
take care of that ODOT. I'm still working with the middle of ODOT by now I'm moving to drive.
And once it's all done, once the building starts getting directed in Gary Pears will come and
he kind of just, he's very, he's very, he's such a sight. And only all of us are getting whatever we got.
Good print questions or whatever. So, but, uh, so.
So we are at 0.3 main, and this is what I've went ahead and brought a couple of the drawings.
What is going to look like?
This is 69 here, and then there's only eight dispensaries out of front.
They're going to be double-sack, and then have part-time in and front, of course, sorely out.
There's probably the big addition that's going to be the decil that's going to be on the north side.
On the north side, we're going to have two high-flow diesel dispensaries for satellite test.
All those who have DEA.
And then on the part of the north side, we're going to have a master, or a master, a DVL-dite cell for pickups.
Anybody who will pull the train or something like that, pull it further than any pickup needs DEA.
This is going to be able to do that.
And we're also going to have an off-road dispenser.
So we've made it.
It could use off-road diesel.
It's going to be available there.
So you're going to have off-road the full game of the diesel.
They're on that side there.
I want to talk to you about, oh, not.
This is a drive that we're moving.
And we're moving that farther to the north.
It's going to be going to allow us to do a 15-degree radius.
We're going to bring that in.
And some all work with the city, and the street department about.
It's bringing that drive where we're going to put a new drive in on the,
oh, what is that road?
Just to the west.
A street.
Yeah, a street.
Just come straight across for easier access out.
So we'll be working with that later.
We're going in with underground storage tanks.
There'll be a 15,000 young, unland.
There'll be 12,000 young in diesel.
6,000 young premium 6,000 young.
EF.
And probably 6,000 young off-road.
So it'll be plenty of storage.
We're also going to park these in the back.
A dumpster containment.
Or instead of just having the dumpers out there,
there will actually be a block containment for gates.
And that will be here to corner.
So the trucks will be able to come in and face right in there.
Get the dumpster garbage in.
So that's kind of what we're looking at there.
This property here, we've just kind of left it alone for now.
So for possibility, it's not just things that are going on.
All this is going to be all under concrete.
From north to southeast to west.
Except for this little area right here.
We're a little leave it for possibility of expansion.
On a street, is there a weight limit that we're going to have to raise or do anything with?
They would turn off that.
You know, I'm dead in the flow, but we would like to flow coming in all 69 and flow straight on.
Do things impossible, but like I said, I don't know how much big trucks, if they're willing.
I mean, when we do a side assessment, we're learning a lot of box trucks.
A lot of pickups that's got needs for all things like that.
We know there's a lot of tractor-turners on the highway that goes across there, but I don't know how much.
This talk is a job when there isn't a job, but we'll get out there.
We think there'll be a lot of secret.
Yeah.
Yeah, all the city of England.
No comment.
Thank you.
All right.
This is the inside of the store layout.
As of today, we have worked over halfway done in our new store and carting right now.
And we've already got changes, or the bulk ends are bigger.
The bike racks are bigger.
It's shifted over.
We've had to loosen the justice in there.
And I'll show you kind of interior.
The restrooms of the women's restroom are placed all in restrooms.
Plains are placed all in a family restaurant.
That will have a little bit of a change in the closet here.
This is all in the walk-in freezer, but you can get their bag ice without going outside.
And that's five door cooler.
Then here in the corners of the beer cave.
And what that is is your 12 pack of 24 pack.
All that is in there.
It's a lower temperature.
So it may be the coldest beer in town.
That's what we try to advertise.
And people actually would go in and get a leave.
And then this year is going to be a 12-door cooler.
We've got all of that.
Then here is our pool kitchen.
And this is the counter to no comment for that.
And then here is our fountain.
And we'll see if you pictures a bit.
And then this year we'll be our car.
So we're seeing actually when I'm short here that W.
Probably at least three table of chairs in there.
That people can sit down and drink coffee or whatever they have.
Just want to sit down and rest.
So that's kind of what we're looking at on him.
That piece we do not like sidewalks.
Because they're a trip hazard.
So it's going to be from the grade of the four of the building.
It will be graded all the way out to 69.
And we'll keep that foot.
We'll put pipe all over the front.
That in and keep for me kind of trip hazards.
That's kind of the generic four plans for this one.
Even though we might change 20 things in the car.
They're already.
So we're finding things that are working a little bit better.
So you said there's you're parking in the back.
Does there a bite door?
Yeah.
I hear it.
Okay.
It's not like a double door.
But it's definitely interesting about it.
Got just yelling me and stop any time you ever remember I'm pretty sure I could go on first
This is what the whole collection was written down
So I think I think we're gonna make you guys proud. But no, this is this a bunch of stories
I look like from your bed. This is all e-fist
with blue bands dark block on the side and then we got
great art
Rock on the sides of the colors and the building is
a 46-foot wide by 100-foot long and that's the area of the belly and that's so
So I just pulled up some pictures of what the entire insight going with like there's your coffee bar and
In this here is your fountain the only difference on the fountain is FPD this frozen beverage
We're gonna have two of those
They are they are very very popular and so we are a
Great change in our party store over 5 to end use over go 12 foot across this is actually going to be
14 foot across so we can put two of those in there with
Two 12-head fountains or two 10-head fountains and
Coffee we're gonna have various coffees and this store this is our materials for
Which is more than you see it's got the
The concrete core it won't have concrete core. We tall from we've tall ever since Rich Hill we've done that in my time
But we will have
It's big it's called being the cat and it actually drives the beam and did your coffee and we'll have it
It's not one we'll have two of those there and some people really park out of town of topping and then you
So that's kind of the coffee bar and and that's the interior look
So it's hot and room pressure every day
That's going to be really close to production
This is a kitchen
What we use is a typical kitchen
And each one of these cubicles that cubicles that are the pizza that you can go there
No, that's the pizza and that's the brocer sauce
We have three different offerings. We got peach food. We got brocer and we got pizza
Pizza is mainly our breakfast program, which is this is a gravy
sausage
This is all these kinds of things. We actually make it out
Roaster is all deep fry really healthy
It's good for you
Matter of fact
Last week
Stop and you're kidding that gizzards because I got my blood work done the day before
So I was good to go
I think one of the hardest I didn't bring now is fish. I think I'm going to brag on it is by some of them
space you ever have. It's a clean white, very good. We have chicken strips and then on the pizza side,
it's simple Simon's pizza. I think it's one of the best pizzas that are around, it's about every
topping you can have plus breadsticks, plus from bowling, Kalazone, all that stuff that we make. So we're
going to have 30 going to have a lot of variations of offering. The only difference is on this
side is you can take it with a walkway here. It's kind of a ritual for our new stores. There's
completely all the way across because eventually we will have kiosks for people who offer
an excellent order for our own stuff. And I'll get into the fact that you can call in orders.
We've got a P-dats pizza. I'll kind of show you some of that. But when you talk about technology,
we had to change. Honestly, COVID may just change to more technology than we have right now.
So it's a good deal. All right, this is the inside of the store. I told you about it.
We're back in freezer. It's kind of the design that we have. It's called a turgon design. We have the
tile on the top and we have labeling about all the food, flavors. And there's about the 12-door
crew over there on the right. Then there's our beer came. The beer came that we're going to have here in
Miami. It's actually going to be one rich in water and one walk through the water. It'll be very,
very similar to that. It's called House of Bruise. I'll be 21 in over a container and so that's what we have there.
In B&C, okay, can this you take an Oklahoma, can you sell liquor? Our liquor? I know Missouri, you can't.
I can't now. Okay, okay, so we'll definitely have that. I'll have you saying in here. But I know
our Missouri school, we just adjusted some of our counters now that have liquor. Okay, this is probably
one of the hot items now. Everybody hates them. They're called cell check out. But two reasons, number one,
people come in, get their stuff, scan it, part it, and go. They don't have to talk to anybody. There's a lot of people
don't like to talk to anybody. The younger generation, I'm finding out. They can't talk to you under
pun, and they're not going to talk to you. So they pound this cell check out. And so what the cell
check out, people have a registered in the middle of the two cell checkouts, and that way there's so many
stand in there, if somebody has any trouble with the cell check out or if they just want to visit with a human. And so they're right there
in the midst of all that. That cell check out has been a pretty popular. We're putting a lot of men. It's
probably not going to be honest with you guys. Another reason is, it's hard to get to probably get a boy
here right now.
Okay, a couple of things that we have that we offer and it's an app on your phone number one
There you go
Store and the demon that works out real well
That one of the neat things we have about the pizza
It would be something that you'll have to download this really really neat and talking about innovation is called scanning go
So scanning go
I don't know if I got to do it like that scanning go is it you have the pizza on your phone
You put your credit card on your phone
I can walk into the store
And when I walk in the register, you actually have to take a selfie
So when you're on this app
When you walk into the store, our register will date
Your picture will pop up on the register
And they'll see you come in
You go to the cooler, you grab your water, scan it, and walk right out the door
And it'll be on the register and say if you just pay for that
It's called scanning go
You have to see anybody talking about you
And this is a very, very popular with what young kids
And tell us because you have everything on the phone
Sounds like it's popular with old kids, so these guys don't even know what they have
I guess
There's a couple of nine kids don't want to talk to you
You have to have it in the life and we just go and tell us about it
Anyway, but it's a really neat app and plus on our pizza
You've got discounts, you've got any kind of programs we've got going on
Like two bottles of water, or two bottles of water, or two bucks
Or any kind of ad like that, you'll get them on your phone
But yeah, the pizza is not
And if you ever go to the app store, that's what it looks like
It's a little black, with a big pee, and it's a pizza program
And that's similar to what it's going to look like with the stack of this picture
So it's going to really fill that lot, really nice
But we appreciate everything, we're hoping to hire probably
Around, we have each other's doors about 23.1 employees
That will be working there
In the city, it ought to be a payroll close to $700,000 a year
That will be generated there in the city itself
And that's just a normal new bill that we set up
If it's bigger than it grows, and there's more employees
If you've got any questions right now that I did my last one
long too on this, but I will say as a person to work for a piece, the city of Miami has
been nothing, but gracious, helpful.
I mean, Travis and I have been working on this for two or three years, and I've won
even this location, we was looking at another location, and we really appreciate the investment
if you guys have bring it to us, and we want to turn around and bring it in best practices
and we really do, we really appreciate your help on all of this, and it's been good.
Everybody, we can talk there from the utility company, street department, everybody's been
just fantastic, and we really appreciate it and we look forward to helping have this thing open
by no real good one.
You're a Christian.
It's cool.
I might be jumping to the gun here just a little bit, do you want to talk about any other locations
or what might happen?
Well, I'll tell you that we've already been in the 44, which is a short right next to the
labs, and we kind of upgraded the cooler doors and stuff, because you know, just a little
work that for some of you may know that we bought the motel, I'm one of the interstate, and
we're going to have a bad option next week, you know, and we may need you to have a good
one, but we're looking at things on the biggest thing is demoing, you know, how
where you get rid of all this stuff and we just turn out, I think I've got Bill Thomas working
on a site map for me now on the boundaries of how it is with the bank there, and then once we
get that bill, that site map dimming to around, we start setting things in, you know, like
a diesel island, or parking, or how we want to do that, but to tell you more, we're going
with that, I don't have a clue right now, until we get that site map down and we kind of play with
how we want to do something like that.
Our other store, a store number 1, no, 10, 10, 10, 10, the store number 10, we're going to, we're
going to do a little work on it, and that's 18th and 9, and we're going to, we're going
to make it up, we'll meet, we'll try to meet, we'll try to try to sometimes, if not, next
week after, on some expansion, we want to do some cooler freezer, some probably, if it won't be as
big as of course, as the news store, but it will not, like, will fix that thing out there.
We're going to probably change the Spencer to around the difference of the ones that are there,
put them in line, think like that one.
Yeah, work, we got a lot of work here in line with what we wanted to do.
Well, I've told you this before and I'll tell you again, I appreciate the investment in our community.
It's going to be really nice to go buy and see that parking lot with something on it, I don't know about these guys at the only time or thing I ever remember being on that lot was a Kodak film developing place
And that's been a while back, so it would be nice to drive by and see something else there
But we are telling our employees that they need to stay here for the new store and that they got a place to stay
We haven't had any date or a job
But I'm going to send a bit on Rusty's comments, thank you to all of you here, so I have a bit of an old integration
You have a job that you're looking out for the best interest of the city, but you're also not going up barriers that are key to somebody that would work out
Because we face some obstacles with other folks including the department of transportation that makes you want to go to an investment
So thank you guys for helping us in our next one, we're going to make a best investment
I don't know, G5 tires are appreciative of the hotel going away
I don't know, I don't know, I don't know, I don't know
If you let us call us
Those that are stripping out of the hotel, they're just trying to help you in doing that
But we have to ask them because we came back
It was going
We had to spread the numbers, spread the gear, it was a hell of the man, we're taking it
What about the old store, the one you're moved from Main and Goodrich
We know it, store around all the tanks and things like
that one. Okay.
Okay. Yeah. Well, thank you.
I think I think we would like to work with them on that as well because I know we've had a few people contact us and they may be good on that spot.
So I think about what I'm talking about, maybe just the people who talked to us put them together with pizza and with them talking,
talking, try to work something out and if it doesn't, then we'll send some mouse that way or unless they find somebody in the meantime.
And just like we've talked to Chris, if you guys know anything about it, it's not that we got right south of us just for that property.
That's the reason why we shipped an over and just in case something doesn't need a whole lot of property, but it would be a nice little plot of landform.
Can you talk about right there between the Kuku and their new building, you're going to leave that open for somebody else.
Yeah.
He needs there a lot too.
All right. Yeah. The questions for Rusty. Thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
I appreciate it.
All right. Number 14. Discussion approval and acceptance of FEMA.
For what I can't read that.
So you're going to vote a DR4438-0016.
Oklahoma City of Mayama acquisition of demolition and foot prom structures.
I'm just Christian McCoy.
Yes. So this is the grant that vote into two guys.
FEMA to do demolition acquisition and demolition of mine.
Resetual properties in three commercial properties that were all flooded and red tech in the 2019 plan.
It's a 75-25 match and 75% of that is 500 new.
We're five hundred million thousand dollars to say you have 25% that we've only budgeted it and we're trying to
so to say that we have that all of our address already and we're just going to see what you to formally accept.
Please.
Thank you.
If you ask me earlier, I find a question, and I do have a question now.
And if you can't answer it, I understand.
Do we know the nine residences and the three businesses?
Everybody's going to have a tactic.
It was a list that we put together a lot of that in preparation for this.
And they're also interested, of course, we start to go through.
What's all this happen?
It's going to have to go through the negotiation process with the owners of those properties.
They've got to realize exactly how much they've had to get for the properties.
All the pins are in insurance that they had, how many plays they had, how much they wanted to be paid,
the government for losses, so that all plays into how much money they're actually going to be offered in the acquisition.
So what if one of them says no?
Then that money goes back and can't move it to another house.
The other thing about this, which isn't a bad thing.
The other thing about people in that understanding is that the deed will be marked,
but that's not available property because it's in the floodplain.
That's part of the reason why we're doing this is because after the re-entering of the floodplain,
we're not letting other structures to be built, to be damaged, to start this process.
I would like to hear.
Do you hear the motion?
I don't see any more questions before we did.
I don't know if they decide not to be cooperative, they're in property.
And some respects can become more and more dysfunctional.
It can become more and more dysfunctional and more of an issue for the city,
because a lot of these properties we are already dealing with,
which we're going to make friends and trying to keep people out of it,
but as she was in an eventually the city ends up demoing that when we get to that point,
they're not getting anything from those properties.
So hopefully, I wonder if these problems realize this is their best opportunity
to re-tube some of the money that they invest in.
Oh, make a motion.
Second.
This is right.
Thank you.
Michael.
Hi.
Davis.
Senator.
Parker.
Hi.
Thank you, Christy.
Number 15.
The initiative petition 2021-102,
proposing an ordinance.
I have the city of mind.
I'm running the rights of residents of my amount to clean water.
I've been learning in Mr. Bechagin.
So this is on the agenda today.
Surely for informational purposes at this time.
I'm not asking for any action to be taken at this time.
It will be presented to you later.
But this is to get you acquainted with what is going on here.
First of all, I point out that this is a.
the position of 2021-2, the position of the position of 2021-2, the position of 2021-1 was filed
earlier after some consultation, that was withdrawn. And then this was filed 2021-2 was
filed on June the 9. Basically, this jam is going to present to you what the petition is about.
I'm just going to talk about the procedures here. The council has essentially three different options
that you can pursue here. The first is you can do nothing and in which case the petition then
goes out to the public and it already is out to the public to sign. And if I did a sufficient number
of legal signatures to the petition, I believe we've calculated that number at 603 signatures
is required, then that petition would go to a vote of the people and the target date for the
vote was a lot to approve. Excuse me, that October the 5th. If the voters approve it, then that becomes
an ordinance in the city. If the voters don't approve it, it doesn't. If they don't get enough ballot signatures,
it goes away. There's a number of things that can happen that are outside of our control.
I'm just talking about what you can do. The second option that you have is at some point in time,
before all that happens, you can approve the ordinance as it is written. And then there is no need for the
election. No need to go gather the signatures, although I think that they plan on doing that.
Anyway, just to show that there's the public support for what they're trying to do. The advantage
of that is that it saves the cost of the election, which is to the city and that cost has been estimated
to be about $5,000. The third option that you have is that we can have an alternate ordinance
draft. And then if the petition goes forward, it gets enough signatures and all that, it goes to vote
of the people, then both votes, it goes to the vote of the people. And whichever one gets the most votes,
is what then becomes the city.
and that, of course, you still are paying the cost of the election, which is so unless there
are any questions on those procedural aspects of it, and I turn it over to Ms. Jam,
or whoever else who's going to speak in regards to the petition.
Thank you very much for the opportunity.
Here we go.
but find that criticism, I should be like,
but in life, in the years, it's the same thing.
The second thing we're asking in this morning is the rights
of the people to possess the right to assist the regenerate
and flourish.
And shall have the right to manage our reach,
the right to flow to our fallen and necessary
to provide habitat for native plants and animals.
And the right to provide plain ones,
the right to free,
the free from pollution,
and the right to restoration.
Tarkridge shall also have the right to be free
from activities or projects that provide what the dryness.
The right to be free,
secure within this ordinance,
shall not be entered deep,
to get further liabilities on it,
should be the creep of
the right to be in the future.
I think that through each of these parts of the land,
but I do want to tell you,
that you've got a new vision to be still not bringing this to you.
We're bringing the forward,
just to the public sector,
and have the James Couch,
John Cole,
who's here to help us.
There are many, many,
that would be likely to be in contact with you soon.
that was quietly running this to me because for now there is a great great design to have a change that is going to work to protect the asset that we have.
This community was built between the river and the river because there was a great value in that.
Freshly running on the river.
I did have questions.
This is the same within the city limits.
So if somebody was to do a project in commerce and it flows down through my own.
So we're preventing anybody from doing anything upstream that would come through there on that.
Was that something we can force me?
Well, I think there are some legal questions that at least right now I don't know the answers to all of them.
This is part of why we're not asking for an action.
But there are a lot of legal questions that I think you would want to know answers on this.
I guess why I'm asking that is because we're saying that we will enforce and if somebody doesn't have a strain then we have to enforce this.
Then legally we're going to be in a battle that we might not be able to win.
I have been helping.
And essentially, see one which deals with the question of pollution in under enforcement.
I believe it's easy one.
That is borrowed and taken virtually weren't forward to be able to hold the environment.
That is a state statute that already exists, sorry, well established.
And the way that that statute of the works is that it gives at a state level the attorney general.
The power to go directly into a district court and final action regarding the public use of citizen calls by pollution.
I cannot say the level of out to propose to you is fact.
I haven't fully researched it.
I tried to slow on Georgia for eight years.
I grew up here in Miami, but I would suggest, and this will, you can probably be searched
this further and find a more definitive answer, but I would suggest that the mechanism
operation of this co-section, this or this, see what we're in, what happens at the state
of level, that is to say, separate and powerful and forceful to be invisible to it.
Maybe we should give the city the authority to go directly into district court, solving your
existential problem, but to be honest, speaking for myself, as a resident of Miami,
my own hope is that the effect of this ordinance is not creating fights, but to create a sense
of connection and unity of purpose among all the communities of all property, and that
it opens up different types of pathways for conversation, about any problems that might
or might not exist in the future, right?
But to your question about the jurisdiction, I believe that this ordinance would operate
in mirror to the way the state's action operates, which is it creates, because it's public
nuisance, creates the ability to go into district court, and address it without having to get
into these complicated questions of the city's authority to act based on something happening
in commerce, but if you have to go there, if something flows into the city, then there's a horn
that's happening to the city, you know, and that's something of this reward I can speak to, I'm
not like since no one will hide, I can't, you know, tell you what the answer isn't
you'd be with life, but I think that the problem there hopefully won't be a dirt of the
problem.
It's probably because it's null, because we're taking this state's action using it in this report,
but they have the benefit of them, you know, you don't have to wait on, you don't have to wait on
the idea, if someone does something wrong, the damage is concrete closer, and how you do that
is a few, you want to take a very comfortable approach and follow an action, but that you can't
do that does not necessarily mean, but it creates the opportunity to say, well if we have
some leverage here, we can file this action in this report, we can file an action in this report,
but that opens up opportunities to face a problem, so that's just a long way to end with
a good choice, someone help you get this question.
I might.
to that Mr. Mayor, the entire time that I was in the legislature, every attorney in the legislature is excused from getting mandatory, continuing legal education that every other attorney has to get every year. Why they do that? I don't know, because those people need to make a educational cut. Because I now have to have to get some CNL keys.
Next month, I'm taking legal education course on water law, because I don't know water law.
And so hopefully that will help in my being able to answer a lot of these questions.
And I support it as well. I just want to make sure that we're up, baiting herself in the court, and getting an ordinance we can't enforce, but we're required to enforce.
So that's all I want to make sure is that we can't enforce what we put in there.
Are we the enforcer, or do we become responsible in some way, for the contamination that flows in here from the north?
No, it was an or. Are we the enforcer of the ordinance solely, or do we have responsibility to clean it up?
Okay.
So I asked President or future.
I don't read it that way.
I read it as he knew that we would be the one that the responsibility of the enforcer.
It doesn't take away the fact that he can be called because he can't wait for the fact that the plan you want to add can be brought forward as it has to be the risk to instance if something.
Okay.
You just allow us the seat to be brought into your part, and you know, spokesperson for the water.
And I believe that what help us in our place to get the whole thing to do.
MP is never had a voice from this city to say the one he's made.
And this will be one really good way to voice that.
Does it give your agency and maybe others some teeth if it's present?
Or maybe instead of teeth and influence.
Okay.
So a lot of the contamination that the creek has on now.
Of course came from the leather seat.
So each time we have a big rainy net more of that comes and that's added pollution.
So that would be new pollution coming down.
So that would be something that you would want us to go.
I think you can think about it.
And I'll tell you, we have three separate.
We're working with some scientists.
And we're just going to put together that I really like to bring the next month to show that I don't have a great deal with this about what's what else is going on.
We know every day there is an S of mine where it'll come together.
We know how much because it's being a nation.
But in S, we're going to let's point to you.
But we also know from this map exactly which piles are closest to that flood plant.
Which may be adding right to us as it's closer to the burning of light.
We can't go to a piece, but we can make this by standing.
Any other questions?
Thank you.
16, the other day business has any as a result since the posting of this agenda.
17 staff reports.
18 mayor and council community and council.
The only one I got is about our Route 66 Heritage Festival.
Thanks you going well.
The man is here.
I think we've got all of our national acts signed and get to go there.
The sponsorships are going well.
You think I'm missing on that?
Yes, I saw that.
Let's go.
reach their goal of seeing so it's kind of together.
A lot of, so a lot of moving cars are permission
and me and team met today, kind of great meeting.
H2 is remote in that as well.
It's a lot of brainstorming that kind of last push
to get that out.
So first of the next week, we will actually see it a lot
now, you will really see a lot next week
in that panel posters.
The car show, part bike show, has some event on a festival page.
You don't like it on Facebook.
You make sure you go on Facebook page.
We'll be adding a marketplace, we'll have it's own events
well on Facebook.
They've two event staff girls that are working with us.
They're thinking ready to start tomorrow.
We work today, and all their packets and information.
But together, they will start going to board a door,
down town to take everybody else, kind of go on.
Street closures, and then they will start going to all restaurants.
Those hotels need just for just really making sure
everybody's aware that it's happening and they didn't need prepared.
Yeah, and those girls are going around, because we want to make sure
the restaurants don't run out of food.
We want to make sure the gas station is running out of gas.
And we want them to be fully prepared about what's coming,
because we've kind of said all along.
We don't really know what to expect, but we're expecting 10,000
plus to come in for the event.
We've been told by some of our sponsors who are undershooting that.
I hope we are, but we've got to be prepared for it either way.
Amanda and her team at the CVB is doing a great job with a limited staff
of getting things done for this to be undertaking.
And we need all the volunteers that we can get to pull this off and
to pull it off without many airs.
We don't want to have some along the way.
So volunteers don't be a must.
And it's going to be all hands on deck to pull this thing off.
But I think we pulled off this first year.
We had a great meeting today, actually,
with some of the Department of Commerce.
And that's all of the people who pulled these numbers together
and have a spreadsheet that they actually
may be able to help us with the next year.
So that was good news.
But I'm excited about it.
I'm looking forward to, Amanda, did you see the peats?
Where did he pop the picture up on their beer cave?
We can call that the peat's beer cave.
His peats is our beer garden sponsor.
The peori tribe is a major sponsor.
Our otter tribe is a major sponsor.
JRDA, the stable's got on board today.
You've got to undergar out one of our contractors.
Olsen is another one of our contractors on board.
So I didn't mention everyone.
There's more.
But we do appreciate all those folks for getting on board
and help us support this.
When you think on something like this,
you're kind of worried that it's not going to happen.
You know, but everything seems to be falling in place and we're about to we're about a month out now
So if you want to volunteer I would volunteer now so you get the spot you want
Because if you don't volunteer, we're probably a volunteer you can put you this spot
Because we're gonna need everything. It's gonna be a big undertaking. So we're gonna need everybody
That's all I got
So we'll go to
About
18 city manager communications
Mr. Mayor counsel I certainly didn't want us to get out of here today without giving you an update on our pool
In all the activity that's been going on there getting the liner in getting it filled doing leak testing
So Kevin Browning or Director of Public Works is with us tonight and since it's been such extensive work in
The timeframe is so critical at this point. I'm gonna have him kind of walk us through what we've done
What we've got left
You have kind of when we think we might be able to have swimmers the liner is fully in
They phased up early last week with the liner
We have start adding water to hold slowly to do the hot air static testing on
The drain
Fancy water to sink the drain all up the valve all up. It is holding so now we're getting pressure from both hands with the flood and the
So that's what you're not well there
We fully expect that it full hopefully by the end of this week and then we go into testing the pumps
filtration system everything else that has been prepared
It all has been prepared. We just need to make sure it all works. What it's supposed to
Right now we're looking for a July 6 opening
We're going to miss the fourth by a couple days, but being a holiday the next day they're close anyway. Oh my day
My six staffing is still going to be a major injury
We do have a covered with part time vehicle the full time guards that have to be certified is tough to get
They had about seven of those certified on Sunday
We're going to hold another certification on June 8 in June 9
It gets rest of them certified
We cannot open that pool without certified off the July 8 the month
July 8 the night so all the kids that didn't get certified this last Sunday
They'll certified July 8 the night
So they're starting to have about 15 when it's all said in that which is plenty to cover what we're going to get
Only four of those are full time rest of our all part times so we're working our at schedules
everything we can do to get kids in there. So if everything goes to bed, we get full full,
we get the pumps, and four hires running, and we're looking at a July 6 update. We are
going to reduce the time by one hour. We're going to go from 1 to 6 to 1, 7. With the lemon
in down there of kids, no breaks. We're going to just work on the straight five hours and then
we're going to have a little bit of a break. So depending on the guards and staffing at that
hay, depends on what slides operate, and everything else. We're hoping we'll have enough.
We think we will, we just have to get it completely full and fire up and see what's leaking
and what's not. The liner itself is not leaking, so if there's going to be any things
that's going to be in filtration, or in the five-band-go-new filtration, which we just had to
get very close to the sun. So the drain is good.
So the drain is good. Now we're up to the jet.
We're right below the jet's right now. The only reason we're below the jet is we have to do a little
retro feeding on the waiting pool drains, which we've got finished today. They'll be installed tomorrow
and then we can fill the rest of the way up. Because the waiting pool fills with the people.
So once we get past the jet, you've got to wait again to see what's we get past the jet,
we won't fire the pumps, that'll test everything else.
So we're hoping that the hay of the jet's tomorrow and then we'll fire the pumps.
It comes fire and the filter's home. We should be good here.
Run through Labor Day since my mom was going to start to spill to us.
So we're going to try. The problem we run into with that is on pole manager and most of our staff,
oh, why not teachers? They go back earlier than the other day.
So we're on that. Looks like we're going to go through that.
I'll get 15th and then try to stay open on the weekends through Labor Day.
We can get my on the teachers on board.
We can check.
But it all goes back to certification.
That lock cart.
We lose a lot of kids going back to school, going back to college.
Just losing.
Yeah.
It's hard to keep them all.
We get it such a late start. It's hard to get them.
Hmm.
Now, if we do the weekends, that at least gives us some time past.
Past our normal closing.
We tried that last year and we just didn't have any attendance.
We had to pull over three, four or five people.
You know, when you're staffing that many people for three or four,
you're going to have to put on that side of the floor.
We're going to have to shut that.
So hopefully get such a late start that.
Don't keep coming on.
It's hard.
Yeah.
And they're definitely using this flash pet.
So as Tyler is watered me over three years in splash.
No.
Thursday, the splash pads have been closed.
Thursday, splash pad will be closed just for we have an annual maintenance inspection
coming out.
Normally, they give us a little more time, fraying, to tell us for them, and they said we need
them out today that they've been here Thursday.
So they'll come in, they'll check all the fittings, the connections, the ball, everything,
just to make sure that things good, and this will be their last rotation on inspections.
We get the website out there that they have the wrong time.
Oh, my wife can be okay with all of this.
She was there waiting, and she saw your websites, so she was there early, calling me when
I wasn't open.
Any other questions for Kevin?
Kevin, thank you for you and your team and all the hard work getting that done.
All the coordination that had to happen just to get us to the point to get the line
to it.
That's been a lot of effort.
That's part of the new line of rain because we didn't have a line of effort.
That was a no easy task, and once, time to get that line of effort.
And I stopped by and talked to the guy that was put in the line of rain a couple of times,
and he was actually the guy that put it in last time in O5, R06, and so this, he was very, well,
knew our pull well, and they did a good job, and he said he was telling me that, just
like Kevin said, you feel slow as a way to go because if we work all the wrinkles out and
make the line of it here good, so I appreciate you, thank you.
Thank you.
Kevin, for the update.
That's all I have.
All right.
Number 20, this meeting will be continued to the Council Chambers and Reconvene and the staff room
for purposes of executive session.